Mss.B.V462
American Philosophical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, 1768-1922; c. 850 items.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 14, 1831; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Hentz, Caroline Lee, 1800-1856; Hentz, Nicholas Marcellus
    Chapel Hill, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for his interest in the tragedy she wrote, which won the $500 prize. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 14, 1831; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Hentz, Caroline Lee, 1800-1856; Hentz, Nicholas Marcellus, 1797-1856
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 23, 1831; 8" x 9 7/8"; Anderson, Richard
    Richmond, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing John Page, and his own son, William Anderson. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 27, 1831; 7 3/4" x 9"; Bulfinch, S. G. (Stephen Greenleaf), 1809-1870
    Augusta, Georgia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing William B. Bacon and his mother. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 29, 1831; 7 7/8" x 9"; Freeman, James, 1759-1835
    Newton, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing his grandson, James Freeman Clarke, and Mr. Taylor. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 3, 1831; 7 1/4" x 8 15/16"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for "kind welcome." Will defer visit to Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, June 26, 1831; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. and Mrs. Brush. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 6, 1831; 7 15/16" x 10"; Physick, Philip Syng, 1768-1837
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for a copy of Divine Government, by Southwood Smith. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, July 20, 1831; 7 13/16" x 9 5/8"; Furness, William Henry, 1802-1896
    Cambridge, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Addison Brown. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 24, 1831; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Walton Hall, near Wakefield, Yorkshire, 1 p. Introducing Mr. Naylor. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 19, 1831; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Sullivan, William
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introduction Robert Treat Paine. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 24, 1831; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Miss Ann Gardiner and Miss Sullivan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 15, 1831; 7 3/8" x 9"; Sedgwick, Catharine Maria, 1789-1867
    Stockbridge, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. George Pomeroy. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 17, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Longfellow, Stephen, 1776-1849
    Portland, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Professor Samuel P. Newman, of Brunswick. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 26, 1832; 4 1/8" x 6 3/4"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Vaughan to send him a copy of an account of the colony of Liberia, published at Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 9, 1832; 8" x 9 1/2"; Sullivan, William
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing his son, James S. Sullivan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 10, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Dunbar, William, MD, 1793-1847
    Natchez, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. and Mrs. Henry W. Huntington. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 10, 1832; 5" x 7 7/8"; Felton, C. C. (Cornelius Conway), 1807-1862
    Cambridge, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. J. S. Dorr. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 6, 1832; 7 15/16" x 9 11/16"; Bowditch, Jonathan Ingersoll, 1806-1889
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Returns thanks for his pleasant visit to Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 7, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Hentz, Nicholas Marcellus, 1797-1856
    Cincinnati, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Encloses a story for Godey's Lady's Book. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 18, 1832; 7 7/8" x 10"; Physick, Philip Syng, 1768-1837
    ----, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for loan of papers from Sir Henry Halford relative to treatment of the gout. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to the president and directors of the New Castle & Frenchtown railroad co., Oct. 1, 1832; 6 1/2" x 9"; Childs, Cephas Grier, 1793-1871
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 24, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Columbia, [S. C.], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Status of political parties in South Carolina. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, November 17, 1832; 4 3/4" x 7 1/2"; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866
    ----, 1 p. A.L.S. Apology for failure to call upon Mr. Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 24, 1833; 8" x 9 3/4"; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding a set of standard weights and measures, which the governor of Pennsylvania shall be authorized to procure. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 9, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864
    Cambridge, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Joseph B. Walker. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 21, 1833; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; Smith, Charles
    ----, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Requests Vaughan to write letters of introduction to his friends in London, to be used by his son, Theodore H. Smith. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 19, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Sullivan, William
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. Francis Leiber. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 11, 1833; 4 7/8" x 8"; Taylor, Richard C.
    Lewistown, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing George Irvington. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 8, 1833; 8" x 10"; Physick, Philip Syng, 1768-1837
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Requests Vaughan to thank Judge Huger for the liberal fee he paid for professional services. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 24, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Clark, William, 1770-1838
    St. Louis, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introduction his sons, Meriwether Lewis Clark and George Rogers Clark. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, August 2, 1833; 8" x 9 7/8"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Charleston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Memmenger and Mr. Bennett. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 7, 1833; 8" x 10"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    University of Virginia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. R. C. Stanard, "a distinguished Alumnus of this Institution." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 16, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Bulfinch, S. G. (Stephen Greenleaf), 1809-1870
    Augusta, Georgia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. John Bacon. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, August 19, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Philadelphia, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. George Clymer, of the U.S. Navy, who "is about to proceed to Paris." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 9, 1833; 8" x 9 3/4"; Cadwalader, Thomas
    ----, 1 p. Forwards sketches of the two sides of his vase, the figures of which he desires to have explained. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 25, 1833; 7 13/16" x 9 13/16"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    Newport, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Discussing his health. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 25, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Jay, William
    Bedford, N. Y., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends autograph of John Jay to John Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 27, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Hentz, Caroline Lee, 1800-1856; Hentz, Nicholas Marcellus, 1797-1856
    Cincinnati, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Success of his wife's plays in Cincinnati. Pelby's failure to perform his engagement. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 27, 1833; 7 7/8" X 9 5/8"; Hentz, Caroline Lee, 1800-1856; Hentz, Nicholas Marcellus, 1797-1856
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 28, 1833; 7 13/16" x 8 3/4"; Benson, B.
    1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Thomas D. Carneal of Cincinnati. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 25, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Mitchell, John Kearsley, 1793-1858
    ----, 1 p. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for gift of sherry wine. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 30, 1833; 7 7/8" x 10"; Channing, Henry, 1760?-1840
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing his son, Dr. William Channing, "who has been several years in Medical Practice in this city." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, 1833; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Beher, Baron
    [Philadelphia], Sunday morning, ----, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. (In French.) Concerning attendance of his traveling companion, Colonel M'Dougall, at the Wistar Party. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 11, 1834; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Henry Bright, "late member for Bristol." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jacob Snider, Jr., May [20?], 1834; Preston, William C.
    Thanks him for the specimens of printing for the use of the blind. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 1, 1834; 6 7/8" x 8 7/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges letter to March 20th. Wants two copies of Say's Insects of North America. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, June 2, 1834; 6 3/8" x 8"; Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849
    New York, 3 pp. Recommends twenty-five Poles "taken up by the City of Philadelphia" to the attention of Mr. Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 3, 1834; 6 1/4" x 7 5/8"; Peddie, James
    Philadelphia, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Theory as to the volcanic origin of coal. Sends four specimens of coal. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 29, 1834; 7 3/4" x 8 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Miss [Harriet] Martineau. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 19, 1834; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Howden, who "visits America with a view of trying his hot air stove." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 19, 1834; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Ware, Henry, 1794-1843
    Cambridge, [Mass.], 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regrets his present inability to visit Mr. Vaughan at Philadelphia. Will send a volume of Priestley's lecture at first opportunity. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 26, 1834; 8" x 9 7/8"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Princeton College, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Jager, professor of natural history at Princeton. FILM 235 FRAME 1. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 27, 1834; 8" x 9 5/8"; Paine, Robert Treat, 1803-1885
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges letter of 22d. Almanac for 1835 to be ready by October. Introduces Mr. Samuel Greele. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to George Willig, Jr., Oct. 8, 1834; 8" x 10"; Friedlander, J. R. (Julius Reinhold), 1803-1839
  - Letter to John [Vaughan], October 22, 1834; 7 3/4" x 10"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    [London], 1 p. A.L.Initialled. Care to be taken in mailing letters, as "inspection... is now become so general & extensive." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 30, 1834; 7 3/4" x 10"; Friedlander, J. R. (Julius Reinhold), 1803-1839
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Charles F. Schenck, a student of medicine. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 18, 1834; 8" x 10"; Physick, Philip Syng, 1768-1837
    Philadelphia, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to trouble in Mr. Singleton's knees. The corruption of bodies after death. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1834; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Friedlander, J. R. (Julius Reinhold), 1803-1839
    Philadelphia, the 14th. 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Regrets that he will be unable to accept an invitation to breakfast with John Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 5, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864
    Cambridge, [Mass.], 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing and recommending Charles Mason. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 8, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Drayton, S. M.
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses donation for the destitute and sick, to be used as Vaughan sees fit. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, January 17, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Perkins, T. H.
    Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Plus 1 p. print. Concerning the vision of futurity of Thomas Say. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 26, 1835; Madison, Dolley, 1768-1849
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Franked: Free James Madison. Acknowledges letter and portrait. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 25, 1835; Tuckerman, Joseph
    Introduces his nephew, Dr. Henry I. Tuckerman. Visited Vaughan’s family in England. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 1, 1835; 4 7/8" x 8"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    ----, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Requests Vaughan to arrange for a seat for his daughter in car to New York. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 17, 1835; 10x8; Izard, J. Allen Smith
    West Point, A.L.S.: J. Allen Smith. 1p.and add. Friendly letter. Plans for his stay in Europe. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 23, 1835; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Cramer, Charles
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Thanks Vaughan for introduction to J.A. Smith [Izard]. Has been admitted to membership in Boston Natural History Society. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 7, 1835; 5" x 7 7/8"; Physick, Philip Syng, 1768-1837
    ----, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Will be happy to receive the Rev. Mr. Porter's visit. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 4, 1836; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Physick, Philip Syng, 1768-1837
    ----, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for sending him Dr. Channing's "last treatise on slavery." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, Jan. 14, 1836; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    1981 45ms
    Formerly B V462.5
    Introduces the mineralogist Edward Hartewood, who wishes to study the riches of our country.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 15, 1836; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Bradford, Alden, 1765-1843
    Boston, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Expresses his regret upon the death of Vaughan's brother [Benjamin] at Hallowell. Founding of Geographical Society in Boston. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 16, 1836; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Columbia, S[outh] Carolina, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Personal and family affairs. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 25, 1836; 6 7/8" x 8 7/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Gay Lussac, "son of the celebrated chemist." Extends his sympathy upon death of Benjamin Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 3, 1836; 8 1/8" x 9 7/8"; Brown, John P.
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses several letters for the consideration of Mr. Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March, 1836?; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Brown, John P.
    ----, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regarding his attempt to obtain the patronage of the Department of State. Need to be examined in the Turkish language. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 4, 1836; 8" x 9 5/8"; Lorich, Severin
    New York, 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Mr. Vaughan authorized to receive and remit to Mr. Lorich the amount due to Andrew Bovart Smith, deceased. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 20, 1836; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Brown, John P.
    Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Mr. Vaughan for his assistance in procuring consulship at Constantinople. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 29, 1836; 5" x 7 7/8"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    L-4 Cambridge, Mass., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards supplement to Catalogue [of Harvard University?] to Library Company of Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Acrostic, addressed to John Vaughan, April 1836
    A poem in his honor. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 3, 1836; 8" x 9 7/8"; Everett, Alexander Hill, 1790-1847
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Whitcomb. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 1, 1836; 6 7/8" x 8 7/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes copy of work entitled, Antiquities of America, by Ira Hill. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 12, 1836; 8" x 9 15/16"; Ingersoll, Joseph R. (Joseph Reed), 1786-1868
    Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards to Mr. Vaughan for the Chamber of Commerce, an arrangement made by Mr. Charles Biddle for crossing the Isthmus of Panama. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 17, 1836; 7 1/2" x 9"; Ferguson, James
    Elizabethtown, [N. J.], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Concerning scientific matters---Weights and measures. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 29, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 3/4"; Brown, John P.
    Constantinople, 4 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Account of trip across Europe to Constantinople. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to the Rev. Mr. Farley [Newport, Oct. 19, 1836; 7 3/4" x 7"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    Portion of A.L.S. 1p. and add. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 29, 1836; 8 1/4" x 10 3/8"; Thacher, Peter Oxenbridge, 1776-1843
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Charles Jackson, Jr. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, November 19, 1836; 7 5/8" x 10 1/4"; Forsyth, John
    Department of State, Washington, 1p. L.S. The Secretary of State refuses to issue a passport to Julius R. Friedlander, a native of Germany. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 28, 1836; 8 1/16" x 9 3/4"; Friedlander, J. R. (Julius Reinhold), 1803-1839
    New-Castle, 1 p. and address. Acknowledges receipt of letter of recommendation sent by Mr. Warren. Boat detained by unfavorable winds. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, December 19, 1836; 8" x 10"; Ingersoll, Joseph R. (Joseph Reed), 1786-1868
    House of Representatives, Washington, 2 pp. A.L.S. Concerning fire in post office building in Washington. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jacob Snider, jr., Dec. 27, 1836; 8" x 10"; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. Establishment of the manufacture of beet sugar in the U.S. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, with recollections of Philadelphia, 1836; c. 40 sheets and scraps with notes referring to Watson’s book, with page numbers.; Mordecai, Jacob
    Includes recollections of Philadelphia, after having read John Fanning Watson’s Annals of Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
    Published in PMHB, April 1974.
  - Will, 1836-1842; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, with codicils of Photo. of A.D.S. 3p. (last codicil only signed by J.V.) Dated Oct. 27, 1836; May 6, 1837; May 18, 1840; Dec. 27, 1841. With this are affidavits of witnesses and executor, Jan 3, 1842 - 3p. From original in Register to Wills office,Phila; presented by John P. Boland, register. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 2, 1837; 7 7/8" x 10 1/8"; Friedlander, J. R. (Julius Reinhold), 1803-1839
    St. Thomas, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Personal affairs. Will leave for St. Croix next week. Wishes Vaughan to forward note to London for collection. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 10, 1837; 4 7/8" x 7 1/2"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Asks Vaughan to recover a debt of 627 fr. 28 ct. from Pennsylvania Library for Foreign Literature. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 28, 1837; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Drake, Daniel, 1785-1852
    Cincinnati, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. Willard Parker, professor of surgery at Cincinnati College. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January, 1837; 7 7/8" x 10"; Howe, S. G. (Samuel Gridley), 1801-1876
    Washington, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. Plans for the education of the blind. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Extracts from letters to Geo. Logan, February 7, 1837; Dickinson, John, 1732-1808
    Copied in a ms. biographical account of the latter drawn up by Mrs. Deborah Logan. Ext. by Jn. Vaughan. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 8, 1837; 8" x 10"; Quinby, J. B.
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. J. B. Ferand, United States consul at Panama. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 18, 1837; 8 3/4" x 10 1/2"; Brown, John P.
    Constantinople, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Desires information on aboriginal languages of America. Terrible ravages of the plague in Constantinople. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 25, 1837; 8" x 10 1/16"; Webb, Thomas H. (Thomas Hopkins), 1801-1866
    Providence, 1p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Catherwood, "the celebrated Traveller in Egypt, Jerusalem, and Palestine." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 30, 1837; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Sedgwick, Catharine Maria, 1789-1867
    New York, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Count Confalonieri and Giovanni Albinola. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, April 8, 1837; 5" x 8"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Washington, 2 pp. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for forwarding to him a review of some (unidentified) articles. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 13, 1837; New York Historical Society.
    Signed Frederic de Peyster. Thanks for publications. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 17, 1837; 9" x 11 1/4"; Hartford Natural History Society
    Hartford, Conn., 2 pp. and address. L.Signed: J. Smyth Rogers. Election of Vaughan as corresponding member Hartford Natural History Soc. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 21, 1837; 8" x 10"; Awl, William M.
    Columbus, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Asks for ground plan of Pennsylvania Institution for the Blind, in order to use the same as a model for a proposed institution in Ohio. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, June 12, 1837; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Short, C. W.